How far would you go to become someone else.
The Talented Mr. Ripley is a thriller, crime, drama
film directed by Anthony Minghella.
Tom Ripley is a calculating young man who believes it's
better to be a fake somebody than a real nobody.
Opportunity knocks in the form of a wealthy U.S.
shipbuilder who hires Tom to travel to Italy to
bring back his playboy son, Dickie.
Ripley worms his way into the idyllic lives of Dickie and his girlfriend,
plunging into a daring scheme of duplicity, lies and murder.
Tom Ripley, played by Matt Damon.
Marge Sherwood, played by Gwyneth Paltrow.
Dickie Greenleaf, played by Jude Law.
Meredith Logue, played by Cate Blanchett.
Freddie Miles, played by Philip Seymour Hoffman.
Peter Smith-Kingsley, played by Jack Davenport.
The Talented Mr.
Ripley is a 1999 American psychological thriller film written and directed by Anthony
Minghella, and based on Patricia Highsmith's 1955 novel of the same title.
Set in the 1950s, it stars Matt Damon as Tom Ripley, a con artist who is sent from New York City to Italy to
convince Dickie Greenleaf (played by Jude Law), a rich and spoiled playboy, to return home.
However, Dickie is not easily swayed, and Ripley becomes
dangerously attached to him and his lifestyle.
Gwyneth Paltrow, Cate Blanchett, and Philip Seymour
Hoffman also appear in supporting roles.
The film was a critical and commercial success,
grossing $128.8 million worldwide.
It received five Academy Award nominations, including Best
Adapted Screenplay and Best Supporting Actor for Law.
The film explores themes of new york city,
friendship, ship, new love, lovesickness.
The tone is emotional and thought_provoking and intense.